Wekesa Andrew

Software Engineer

Address: Chwa Road, Kampala, Uganda

Phone: +256 788 057839

E-mail: andrew.christoandrew.christo@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/andrew-

wekesa-4aa27992

GitHub:

https://github.com/christoandrew https://github.com/christo-andrew

Website:

https://christoandrew.github.io

Full-stack Engineer offering 5+ years of experience well versed with both frontend and backend frameworks. I am self-motivated and have a keen interest in developing highly scalable systems using agile methodologies and best practices while ensuring that I have clean and well-researched solutions.

Skills

Frontend frameworks (Angular, Next.js)

Backend Frameworks (Django/Python, Flask/Python, Express/NodeJS, Go/gin)

REST API design

Databases (Postgres, MySQL, MongoDB)

AWS Eco-system (EC2, EBS, RDS, Lambda functions)

Mobile Application Development (Android - Java, Kotlin, Ionic)

Configuration Management and Orchestration (Docker, Ansible, Kubernetes)

Build automation and delivery (Jenkins, CircleCI)

Engineering and Operational Excellence

Soft Skills

- Teamwork.
- Accountability.
- Approachable.
- Creative and Analytical Thinker
- Avid problem solver.
- Good communication.

Work History

2018-01 - Current

Software Engineer

Fenix International Inc, Kampala, Uganda

- Maintain FenixDB core backend in Django
- Build an android application in Kotlin that helped slash costs of operation by 60% and increased sales by up to 40%.
- Built a secure REST API using Django Rest Framework on top of the core backend that is scalable to handle thousands of users across at least 6 countries in Africa.
- Implement and use git flow with GitHub and git
- Use agile tools like Scrum, Kanban.
- Implement a CI/CD solution with Jenkins that made work with QA ~10 times easier.
- Unit testing applications in Android using espresso, Mockito and JUnit and pytest for python with target coverage of up to 80%.
- Document business requirements and work with product managers to ensure that requirements are communicated accurately.
- Provide technical support for products.

2017-09 - 2017-12

Backend Engineer

Huguso Technologies, Kampala, Uganda

- Do code reviews and mentor junior developers.
- Develop and maintain core backend in Flask backed by Postgres Database.
- Integrate Xero (Online accounting platform) API.
- Designed and implemented a CI/CD solution with Amazon Code Pipeline.
- Built an API to process incoming payments from Mobile Money providers.
- Manage and automate deployments to Amazon Elastic Beanstalk.
- Provide necessary support to clients.

2016-01 - 2017-08

Software Developer

iConaSystems Ltd - Kampala

- Designed and implemented a web application that enabled uses to book tickets for public transport online in Ruby on Rails backed by Postgres as Database.
- Unit testing with Jasmine and Karma achieving coverage of at least 80%.
- Implemented Git for version control.
- Design and Implement CI/CD solutions using code and Heroku.
- Developed a Tour and Travel application that allowed users to be able to check and book packages at a cost friendly price.
- API design and implementation using RailsAPI along with a custom CRM to manage application data scalable to handle up-to 95% of the traffic while ensuring good user experience.

2014-01 - 2015-11

Software Developer

Rainbow Connection Ltd, Kampala, Uganda

- Working alongside the senior developers to maintain existing code base.
- Preparing presentations and keeping clients up to speed with the development process.

Education

2012-01 - 2015-01

Bachelor of Science: Software Engineering

Makerere University - Kampala

2006-01 - 2010-01

Certificate: Ordinary Level Certificate, Advanced Level Certificate

Busoga College Mwiri

Mathematics, Physics, Chemistry, Architectural Technical Drawing

Languages

English

Swahili

Interests

Travel and Adventure

Reading